<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tommaso Colella | SWE</title>
    <link>https://gioleppe.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tommaso Colella | SWE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gioleppe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploying AzureOpenAI Service using OpenTofu</title>
      <link>https://gioleppe.github.io/posts/azure-openai-opentofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gioleppe.github.io/posts/azure-openai-opentofu/</guid>
      <description>Lately, some friends have asked me to cooperate on a scientific paper regarding LLMs. As part of this collaboration, I had to assess the feasibility of the automatic deployment of an LLM on a public cloud.
I&amp;rsquo;m lucky enough to work at a company focusing on AI and Microsoft-oriented system integration, and we&amp;rsquo;re always looking for new ways to bring value to the market using cutting-edge services. For this reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with the AzureOpenAi Service for a while: it offers business users the possibility to leverage the power of OpenAi&amp;rsquo;s most advanced models, such as GPT-4 Turbo, without sharing confidential organization data with third parties.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://gioleppe.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gioleppe.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a Software Engineer based in Florence, Italy. I have a BSc in Computer Science from the University of Pisa, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently completing my MSc.
I’m working as Tech Lead and Cloud Architect for Avanade.
My interests lie in distributed architectures, LLMs, and programming languages. You can find me either writing code or listening to music by some unknown band.
Stuff I&amp;rsquo;m experienced into Azure and Cloud-native architectures DevOps methodologies (IaC, CI/CD) Developing and integrating REST APIs Integrating payment processors Working on legacy code Working with both SQL and noSQL DBMSs Docker and Docker Compose Unit Testing Developing Telegram bots (C# and Python bindings) git (git flow, conventional commits, hooks) Agile methodologies Languages/Frameworks I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with C#/.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
